<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Joe Hand</title><link href="http://joeahand.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://joeahand.com/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://joeahand.com/</id><updated>2014-06-26T21:22:45-06:00</updated><entry><title>The Shockingly Simple Math Behind Early Retirement</title><link href="http://joeahand.com/archive/the-shockingly-simple-math-behind-early-retirement/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-06-14T11:19:28-06:00</updated><author><name>Joe Hand</name></author><id>tag:joeahand.com,2014-06-14:archive/the-shockingly-simple-math-behind-early-retirement/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;There are countless blog posts about how to save for retirement. &lt;a href="http://www.mrmoneymustache.com/2012/01/13/the-shockingly-simple-math-behind-early-retirement/"&gt;In this post&lt;/a&gt; Mr. Money Mustache presents an amazingly simple and shockingly effective way to look at retirement; the amount of time until you can retire is simple a function of your savings rate. What doesn't matter? Your income, your spending, your age, or anything else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only is the equation simple, the idea behind it is very powerful. Looking at the table he presents, you can see that by increasing your savings from 10% to 15% you can chop 8 years off your time until retirement. Wow!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason this works? In order to increase your savings rate, you probably have to decrease your spending. This means that you will be able to live off less for the rest of your life. And your money saved will be compounded over time. So, there are some strict assumptions in there. But the idea behind everything is very intriguing, and I suggest you at least &lt;a href="http://www.mrmoneymustache.com/2012/01/13/the-shockingly-simple-math-behind-early-retirement/"&gt;take a look&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just discovered the Mr. Money Mustache site but already it has become an invaluable resource on financial advice for me. It bucks much of the conventional wisdom and focuses on spending less through decreased consumption, an idea that is close to my heart. Not only does it leads to more happiness, it helps our planet as well. &lt;a href="http://www.mrmoneymustache.com/2013/02/22/getting-rich-from-zero-to-hero-in-one-blog-post/"&gt;Read away&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>The Reed College Experience</title><link href="http://joeahand.com/archive/the-reed-college-experience/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-03-03T23:26:36-07:00</updated><author><name>Joe Hand</name></author><id>tag:joeahand.com,2014-03-03:archive/the-reed-college-experience/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Reed College experience is often hard to capture. The latest Reed Magazine has a great history of the Reed experience and how it came to be. At Reed you "think about thinking" and learn reasoning by doing. During the process you realize “you are not your ideas, but merely a holder of your ideas.” But this all relies on a open process that does not define a starting and ending point:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"If, on some level, we know what the learning system wants from us—say, by the use of grades as feedback on a defined path toward earning a degree to enter a specific career—we can erect certain internal defenses that allow us to choose how much of ourselves we give away to the system. But when the contract with the system is as existential as learning for the sake of learning, and progress is measured more qualitatively than quantitatively, we are apt to lose some of our psychic protections, allowing the system to get more deeply into our heads."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Writing Matters</title><link href="http://joeahand.com/archive/writing-matters/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-02-15T21:28:16-07:00</updated><author><name>Joe Hand</name></author><id>tag:joeahand.com,2014-01-30:archive/writing-matters/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://randsinrepose.com/"&gt;Rands in Repose&lt;/a&gt; writes great articles about technology and management; his writing is something I admire. Looking through the &lt;a href="http://randsinrepose.com/archives/"&gt;post archives&lt;/a&gt; on his site is overwhelming but also motivating. Scrolling to the bottom you pass a total of 460 posts over the course of twelve years &amp;mdash; this is the overwhelming part. When you finally make it to the bottom you see the motivating bit, the first group of posts from 2002. Here are the titles for the Rands' first four posts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First Entry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No Title&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No Title&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No Title&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like many of us, Rands started from scratch and started simply. He did not have a brilliant series of first posts. But he started and kept taking step after step. Through practice he became a great blogger. The graph below shows that his first few years he put in the most work on the blog, but after that he cruised at around 20 posts per year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Posts Per Year on Rands in Repose" src="https://joehand_blog.s3.amazonaws.com/imgs/writing-matters-Rands-posts.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The amount of writing he did in the first three years is impressive. What what his motivation? Solving problems, making things happen, communicating ideas. In his first post he declared:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IF YOU DON’T WRITE IT DOWN IT NEVER HAPPENED.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Writing Matters&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this world of realtime video and immediate communication technology, it is odd to think that writing is important. But it is actually more important now than ever. The medium of writing used to be confined to books and papers or similar one-time productions. Now writing is rampant. Most communication now happens with writing (emails, tweets, texts, comments) where it used to be dominated by in-person meetings or calls. More people can publish their writing than ever before, with just the click of a button. Now, more than ever, it is crucial to be able to communicate through the written word.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing is important not just to communicate to others, but to communicate with yourself. Writing allows you to save ideas, build on them, create a comprehensive story around a single subject. Writing down ideas creates building blocks. You craft one part of your argument at a time until you have a cohesive structure. This is nearly impossible to do in your head alone. The act of writing itself helps to explore your idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much later in Rands’ writing career he wrote about &lt;a href="http://randsinrepose.com/archives/why-you-should/"&gt;why you should weblog&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exercise your ability to express yourself in words.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re reading this, you’ve chosen to use the web as a means of gathering new ideas. It is a non-trivial ability to take that drunken thought you had last Thursday and translate it a compelling argument that folks should talk about. Writing takes time and practice and time and practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you create a space in your life for a weblog, you’re saying, “Writing matters.” You may not give a shit about writing, you may want to tell the world how much you think are physics is really cool, but to do so, you will need to write coherently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have taken advantage of the writing of others to learn and create a better life for myself. I recognized that  &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;writing matters&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. And finally, I am going to do something about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the first step, a first post. And I need to take step after step once this is done and continue to build on this idea that writing matters, because &lt;em&gt;writing takes time and practice and time and practice.&lt;/em&gt; Like Rands, I hope someday I can scroll through my lengthy archives, look at this first post, and laugh at how far I have come.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Escape from South Africa</title><link href="http://joeahand.com/archive/escape-from-south-africa/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-02-12T23:49:03-07:00</updated><author><name>Joe Hand</name></author><id>tag:joeahand.com,2013-07-02:archive/escape-from-south-africa/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Sweat dripping and the hum of the fluorescents made for a soothing combination of sounds, but I was focusing on something else. Two immigration officers were in the next room discussing my passport, or perhaps it was my sister’s? I listened, but I could not understand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I sat in a dank room, walls grim, worn carpet, and cheap chairs. Federal offices all over the world must order from the same catalog. Another gentlemen from an undisclosed country waited with me. I sat wiping sweat off my brow, he paced. Was this a nightmare? Fevered hallucinations? No, this was my attempted escape from the Johannesburg airport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, I had flu but was I really that compromised? Scenarios ran through my head. It was useless. My exit out of South Africa sat in the hands of the portly officer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fourteen days prior I blissfully boarded my plane from Frankfurt to Johannesburg. I was heading to Africa for the first time. My mind full of anticipation, wonder, and excitement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ten hours later I am preparing for my way through immigration, someone will scan my passport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You see, my passport has two odd features I discovered right before my trip. First, my picture is from when I was fifteen. I have long hair. Oh, and I could easily be mistaken for a girl. Look closely and you may recognize me. But there’s something else…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="emp"&gt;The gender on my passport says female. I’m unmistakably male.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;strong&gt;Notice the “F” under Sex&lt;/strong&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
        &lt;img src="https://d233eq3e3p3cv0.cloudfront.net/max/1876/0*XwOJlQ-ErrMahIvQ.jpeg"&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Sneaking into South Africa&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The line for entering South Africa is long and painful. After two ten hour sleepless flights I am exhausted. Rather than try to explain my gender situation I decide to feign ignorance. Two passport checks in Germany were no problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hand the immigration officer my passport and I wait, nervously. First she questions the picture. I try to explain, I’ve changed, I was young then, fifteen. She looks at gender inquisitively. She asks, and what is your gender?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m male, of course. Unfortunately, my passport does not say male. The officer asks, “Why do you have your sister’s passport?” I act confused. She kindly points out the error and I am aghast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve never been good at acting. She directs me to sit in the corner, dunce cap on while waiting for the supervisor, clocks tick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My passport makes rounds. The supervisor asks fellow officers if the person in the picture is male or female. They ask me why I have my sisters passport. My confidence is shaky. I am not sure if I will ever touch the soil of South africa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I present my drivers license, I feel a hint of encouragement. I explain that I am here for work and am presenting the next day. After more discussion and a scolding for having a ten year old passport that incorrectly identifies me as a girl, they reluctantly let me in, phew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Judgement Day&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My journey home is filled with anxiety. I worry again about my passport, whether I will be able to get home. I know they have stricter immigration checks than most other countries. I never imagined what was ahead for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I leave Cape Town with a sore throat, a runny nose, and a slight fever. I arrive in Johannesburg with a terrible fever and stomach ache, barely able to utter a word. With a few hours before my connection I must find medicine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily the first store after getting off the plane was a full-fledged pharmacy. After trying to navigate the mostly-Afrikaans labeled medicine I get in line for the pharmacist. The gentleman in front of me explains his daughters symptoms, they are exactly what I am feeling. I buy the same medicine and walk out with relief.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After visiting the restroom and taking my medicine I start making my way to my gate. I begin sweating as I schlepp my bags through the airport. As I get closer and closer I realized I have to go through security again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m confident, South African airport security seems relaxed. I prepare my bags, chug my water, and get in line. As I get closer I see another line after security, passport control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hoped the passport control was casual, similar to Germany. They scrutinize your passport getting into a country, I never imagined it would be hard to get out of a country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I joined the queue I realized this could be the beginning of my nightmare. And it came earlier than expected. The line crawls. And it wasn’t for a lack of people checking passports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While waiting in line I survey the immigration officers. I tried to find a reasonable one. I rule out one, he looks terrifying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I drew him, of course! I presented my passport, damp with perspiration. His eyes set on the passport then he looks up at me. And again. And again. UP, down, up , down.Then comes the question I never expected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“This is not your passport. Where is your passport?”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m dead silent. I nervously point out that my picture is old and I am a male even though it says female. I try to explain that it is mine. He quickly calls someone else over and says something I don’t understand. I am pulled aside and he tells me to go with him. Oh no.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weighted with luggage and sweat I struggle to keep up with my leader. We wander through the terminal, seemingly endless, before exiting through a side door. After an enduring set of stairs, locked doors with fingerprint security, and several long poorly lit hallways we end up in the requisite federal waiting room. My passport and ticket are ripped from my hands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m drenched. The passport draws a furious discussion between officers as they study the picture. One officer pokes her head in to get a closer look. The other sketchy-passport refugee joins me and begins pacing. Finally, I am summed to the supervisors office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am grilled on the details of my passport: why did you not correct your passport, what are you doing in South Africa, where are you going? I try to explain my situation. I present my license and offer my full wallet for evidence. He stays quiet but keeps shaking his head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He’s holding my ticket. I have ten minutes until boarding closes. After some hesitation he calls in his colleague to escort me back to the original passport control. I breath a silent sigh of relief, hoping this means freedom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once we start moving the officer asks me which line I came from. We are in the caverns of this airport. So many stairs, and hallways, passing doors, and I have a terrible fever. I am lost. I declare my utter state of delirium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are back in the main terminal. He asks again “Don’t you remember what line you were in?” Finally, I get my bearings and we make our way back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we approach the officer who originally sent me away, my nerves return. I go through the same process showing him my license, explaining my situation, and perspiring. It’s clear he does not want to let me through but knows his supervisor approved it. He writes down all of my information, looks at my ticket and tells me to run, fast!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I give a quick thanks and start running. Running away. Running toward freedom, at least temporary freedom. All I want to do is sit, have some water, and sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m running for what seems like miles. I break and realize I am departing from the furthest gate. I keep running and running, catching my breath, resting on the electric sidewalk , and then my last sprint to the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I see the gate, the door is still open. I made it. Coughing and winded but with a lighter heart I hand my boarding ticket and passport to the gate attendant. And then the question comes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Are you sure this is you?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trying to stay composed I tell her I have changed a lot in the last ten year. She laughs and tells me I have really grown into a man and motions me onto the plane. I made it. I made it. I made it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Home Sweet Home&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the plane ride I pass through three mental states: sleep, feverous delusion, and distress about getting through Germany and into the US.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find luck in Germany by missing any of the passport control stations. I enjoy my connection there like no other flight connection I have ever had. I feel like the king of the world, free to move about Terminal 1-Z doing whatever I please.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The huge airbus A380" src="https://d233eq3e3p3cv0.cloudfront.net/max/2560/0*yz0zMb9xzx6bQlI4.jpeg" /&gt; My tranquil state carries over for most of the flight to the US. I get to fly one of the double-decker Airbus planes for the first time. I enjoy my last moments of freedom. We are handed the US customs forms and the hammer of reality drops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once again, in the passport line and my mind is racing. What do I say? How do I tell them it is really me?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="emp"&gt;I decide to be my true self and explain my situation honestly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I approach the US immigration officer,no expectations. I hand him my passport, explaining my situation. There is an error on my passport. I found out about it right before my trip, I did not have time to change it. The picture is from many years ago. I had long hair, and yes, And don’t worry, I submitted the application for an error correction today. I have a drivers license if that helps. I am not sure what to do, I barely got out of South Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He stays silent. He looks at me, looks at my passport, scans the passport, and examines my drivers license. And finally he speaks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Are you sure you didn’t get a gender change operation on the plane?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deep, uncontrollable laughter releases days worth of tension, I tell him no, I have always been a male. Contrary to all expectations he explains how I can get my passport fixed and that I can probably get a new longer expiration time out of it for free. Then he stamps my customs document and sends me on my way. The relief is palatable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rest of the journey home has its hiccups but I know I can get there. It may be painful, full of delays, bloody noses, and dehydration, but I can make it without worrying about my passport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And don’t worry, I submitted the application for an error correction today. No longer will I be flying as my sister. Or a female fifteen year-old male. Or anyone but myself. Because in the end being true to who I am is the best way out of a very sticky situation.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>The Start of My Standing Desk Experiment</title><link href="http://joeahand.com/archive/standing-desk-begins/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-02-09T03:25:08-07:00</updated><author><name>Joe Hand</name></author><id>tag:joeahand.com,2013-02-21:archive/standing-desk-begins/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I began a new job with the Santa Fe Institute a few weeks ago. With a new job comes many changes. One change that I am very excited about is the chance to finally use a standing desk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have always been averse to spending all of my working hours sitting at a desk. I tried simple solutions like taking lots of breaks or using an exercise ball but that never solved the problem itself, sitting. Sitting caused my hip flexors and hamstrings to shorten which has been a continual source of pain and injury for me. I spent lots of time doing exercises to mitigate the effects but they always felt fruitless after spending eight hours a day sitting. The solution was staring at my face for ages, a standing desk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I continued to read article after article of the benefits of a standing desk but I could never convince my employer to allow me a standing desk. Once I started at the Santa Fe Institute I asked during my orientation whether that was an option. I was lucky enough to procure the only standing desk in the facility. Even luckier for me, the desk is adjustable!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similar to sitting, the ergonomic set up is important - perhaps even more so with standing. I am still working out the subtleties. I have the desk at the right height; the monitor may need some adjustment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My biggest worry so far is my feet, especially with my achilles issue. The floor is carpeted. I wear my &lt;a href="http://www.vivobarefoot.com/us/mens/gobi-black.html"&gt;vivo barefoot&lt;/a&gt; shoes to work (highly recommended shoes) so there is minimal padding there, by design. I think the barefoot style shoes are important but I may have to invest in a more padded surface to stand on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So now begins my standing desk experiment. I am monitoring my time standing/sitting using the &lt;a href="http://www.standingclock.com/"&gt;standing clock&lt;/a&gt;. I have also been taking daily measurements of my weight so I will use that as a quantitative measure of the effects along with my qualitative observations. I look forward for what is to come!&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Bookend The Day With Routines</title><link href="http://joeahand.com/archive/routine/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-02-09T03:43:10-07:00</updated><author><name>Joe Hand</name></author><id>tag:joeahand.com,2012-07-14:archive/routine/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Lately I have been honing in on my routines. This started with the idea of focusing on one habit each month. The first habit I developed was doing a daily morning walk. Since starting, I have habitually gone for a walk each and every morning. And I love it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Building Habits&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been struggling with my habit this month. I am trying to meditate every day, and I have failed more often than not. &lt;a href="http://artofmanliness.com/2011/09/05/bookend-your-day-the-power-of-morning-and-evening-routines/"&gt;This post&lt;/a&gt; on The Art of Manliness made me think about developing my morning and evening routines to build my habit each month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;My Routines&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thinking through my routines today, I created three lists:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ideal Morning and Evening Routine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First Step Morning and Evening Routine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Current Morning and Evening Routine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moving backwards made me realize how far I have to go to reach my ideal routines! Right now my evening routine is nonexistent. So, I have some work to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Baby Steps&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When building habits, taking small steps is the only way to success. I also created some &lt;strong&gt;rules&lt;/strong&gt; for the morning and evening I have to stick by, regardless of where I am in my routine. This will help me address worries I had (feeling rushed meditating, looking at internet too long at night, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Morning Routine&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My morning routine will look like this starting tomorrow:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Walk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write &lt;a href="http://750words.com"&gt;750 words&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eat Real Food (Meat and Veggies) &amp;amp; Clean Dishes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Meditate&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Teeth Care (Floss/Brush)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dress, Etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only new thing here is meditation. I am also switching the order of eating and writing my 750 words. I have found it a bit hard to write after eating, I seem to get easily distracted by the internet during eating and that delay's my writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Morning Rules:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No internet until 750 words are written.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clean dishes before meditation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start meditation by 7:30am.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Determine topic for evening writing (during 750 words).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My morning routine has been pretty stable over the last year. Whenever I add stuff in (morning walk), it seems pretty easy for me to get it done. I have a lot of willpower in the morning!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Evening Routine&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, I struggle with my evening routine. Between having a varied schedule for dinner, cooking, crossfit, or going out and not being sure what I want to do - I end up spending a lot of time just surfing the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope by establishing a list of things I &lt;strong&gt;must&lt;/strong&gt; do and times for when things to be done, I can do a better job of this. This list is going to be much shorter because I am just jumping into the whole evening routine thing. Baby steps!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clean up dishes after dinner&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Focused writing on a single topic&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review goals, habits, day, life&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The focused writing is something new. I always &lt;em&gt;intend&lt;/em&gt; to write a blog at night, but find it hard to figure out the topic and then focus. That is where morning rule #3 comes in!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other items in this list are things I have done with some regularity. But I hope to do them daily now (off and on...).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Evening Rules:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No electronics after 8pm.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start review by 8:30pm.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clean all dishes, put away clothes, etc, before reviewing goals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thats it! I have a ways to go to reach my ideal routine. For now, one step is enough.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>It's my birthday!</title><link href="http://joeahand.com/archive/my-birthday/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-02-09T03:03:43-07:00</updated><author><name>Joe Hand</name></author><id>tag:joeahand.com,2012-06-21:archive/my-birthday/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today marks a quarter century since I was born. It also marks the first day of summer, though this year was one of the rare years the my birthday and the solstice did not coincide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I joined some friends for a beautiful picnic last night in Portland's Rose Garden. Great friends, great food, nice weather, flowers, and some good wine. Not much more you need for a good birthday celebration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have thought a lot about living a long life. I hope this quarter century marks the first of six in my life. 150 seems like a long life. But I will be sure to enjoy every day of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy first day of summer!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;=)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also - just for the record - biking home with a bunch of balloons tied to your back is pretty fun. I would recommend it.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Creating the habit of creating habits</title><link href="http://joeahand.com/archive/the-habit-of-habits/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-03-11T17:41:00-06:00</updated><author><name>Joe Hand</name></author><id>tag:joeahand.com,2012-06-18:archive/the-habit-of-habits/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Creating a habit in a tricky thing. At first it seems so simple. You wake up and floss your teeth. Boom, done. Next day - you almost forget but then remember, teeth flossed. Then the third day you may forget or put it off until the day it done. And eventually you keep putting it off and it does not get done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting a new habit is not something you can just jump into. You must slowly approach it so as to not scare it off. Then you need to coddle it, never let it leave your side for a month. After a month it starts to grow. But it can still escape if you are not careful. Every week you must reconnect with it. Remind yourself why you are building this habit and what you hope to achieve. After a couple months your habit may finally blossom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a science to habits, literally. There are millions or even billions of dollars in creatings habits. Companies try to get you in the habit of buying their product. Grocery stores get you in the habit of buying a treat, just this one time, in the checkout line. If you approach habits with the same careful scientific mindset, you can get in the habit of creating habits.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Experiments in Kindness</title><link href="http://joeahand.com/archive/experiments-in-kindness/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-06-26T21:22:45-06:00</updated><author><name>Joe Hand</name></author><id>tag:joeahand.com,2011-08-01:archive/experiments-in-kindness/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On June 29th 2011, one week and one day after turning 24, I set out on a mission. The mission: make some yummy chocolate chip cookies. Something about making chocolate chip cookies always strikes the right notes with me. When I bake my soul is at ease. Me and the cookies are one. I am not sure what it is; part science, part chocolate, lots of sugar, and of course, smiles. People love cookies and I love making people smile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After I had lots of cookies, I needed someone to eat them. Deciding to give them to cyclists heading home from work was the easy part. The real inspiration struck me while reading about the ongoing conflict in Ladd's Circle. And so my first Experiment in Kindness was born.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The response of the complete strangers receiving cookies amazed me. I cannot remember a better bike ride than the one returning home after that experience. It did not take long for me to launch &lt;a href="http://smilingjoe.com"&gt;smilingjoe.com&lt;/a&gt; and make it a goal to keep my experiments going.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kindness begets kindness. We can each make the world a better place with kindnesses small or large. Even if my experiments fail or stop completely, I know that for that one day, in those 30 minutes, I put smiles on 100 faces and that is enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The day always looks brighter from behind a smile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Unknown&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Finding Your Smile</title><link href="http://joeahand.com/archive/find-smile/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-03-11T17:38:45-06:00</updated><author><name>Joe Hand</name></author><id>tag:joeahand.com,2011-07-23:archive/find-smile/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Find your smile just like you find your voice. Start by smiling a lot.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Me and Writing&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout school I never enjoyed writing. Everything always felt forced as I tried to conform to standards. I ended up writing with someone else's voice leading to terrible papers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After writing the experiments in kindness and some personal blog posts, I realized how much I enjoyed writing -- on my terms. But I still felt I needed to work on getting my ideas down with clarity and ease. Any writer will tell you that in order to learn how to write, you write, a lot. So, six days ago I made it a goal to post here everyday for thirty days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Serendipity&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Five posts later and I am making progress, but sometimes only with great effort and frustration. I still feel like I am &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;finding my voice&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. As I began writing today I struggled to start. I headed over to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://zenhabits.net"&gt;ZenHabits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; by &lt;a href="http://leobabauta.com"&gt;Leo Babauta&lt;/a&gt;, my favorite source for motivation. Lo and behold, a post on &lt;a href="http://zenhabits.net/voice/"&gt;finding your voice&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first tip as expected, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Write a lot&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Check. The second tip: &amp;gt;&lt;strong&gt;Experiment boldly&lt;/strong&gt;. Rip off the greats, and the goods as well. Mimic and make it your own. Try and err.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I kept reading and within moments I began seeing how finding your voice parallels finding your smile. I decided to "rip off the greats... mimic and make it my own." And thanks to ZenHabits being in the &lt;a href="http://zenhabits.net/open-source-blogging-feel-free-to-steal-my-content/"&gt;public domain&lt;/a&gt; I could do so easily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you Leo for all the great posts and inspiration. If I could only read one blog the rest of my life, I would choose ZenHabits. I encourage everyone to check out &lt;a href="http://zenhabits.net"&gt;ZenHabits&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The remainder of this post was stolen from there and modified without regret.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; I lay claim to none of the hard work and words you will find below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Finding Your &lt;strike&gt;Voice&lt;/strike&gt; Smile&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Humans of any kind must find their smile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are writers, musicians, designers, programmers, parents, builders of anything. But we are not truly at peace with ourselves, and genuinely happy, until we've found our smile: the attitude, kindness, compassion, love, personality we use to express ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our smile is our essence, plain for the world to see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A fellow happiness seeker asked me how I found my smile. And I have no easy answer -- I'm not even sure I can say I've fully found my smile yet. It's a quest that doesn't seem to end -- not a Grail quest, really, but a constant retuning as the essence of who I am neverendingly changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I feel I've found something that has the texture of truth, even if only a tactile approximation. I'll share some of my thoughts, but keep in mind I don't hold the answers firmly at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm learning, and I hope my learning helps yours. This is written for smile seekers, but the ideas are the same for anyone who is human.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Smile a lot.&lt;/strong&gt; This is almost all I need to say, as nothing else matters without the constant practice of smiling a lot. Try smiling right when you wake up, when you are washing dishes, smile to strangers, find your enemies and smile with them, smile at nature, and smile for yourself. The sheer mass of your smiles becomes the raw matter from which to chisel your happiness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Experiment boldly.&lt;/strong&gt; Rip off the greats, and the goods as well. Mimick and make it your own. Try and err.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learn to be at peace with yourself.&lt;/strong&gt; My smile is really the happiness in my head. It's not how I assert my happiness, but how I feel my genuine happiness, in the noisy cavern of my skull. I listen to my inner peace and that's the smile I try to emulate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting that happiness from your head to your face -- that's the trick. It's not easy, but again, do it often, and you'll get proficient at it. It's a rewiring of the synapses, so that your head-happiness shoots down into your face muscles and come out as a smile, as kindness and compassion. Most people don't do this enough to get good at it, and so there is low fidelity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Find what feels true.&lt;/strong&gt; You'll smile a lot, and most of it will be bullshit. You need bullshit if you want to find the truth. Sort through the bullshit until you recognize the truth, by feel, not by and logical criteria. The truth looks remarkably like bullshit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Find clarity.&lt;/strong&gt; Good smiling, it's been said often, is inner peace. If your inner peace is muddled, your smile will be. I'd recommend a self-taught course on meditation, but really I've found it's a matter of simplifying. Practice removing external desires and agendas until you have only what's needed to express a simple smile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Remove the negativity.&lt;/strong&gt; It's a process of subtraction more than addition. Most people end up with too many feelings, because they never subtract. Negative feelings get in the way of your smile, so pare it down, trimming the cynical from the bush until you're left with truth. I subtract in my head, these days, but that's from years of practice. After you react, acknowledge your feelings, and remove the negativity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most people also have too many detrimental feelings in their own lives to hear their own optimism. Too much is going on around them, and online, and they have no time for solitude. You can't hear your happiness, your inner peace, without solitude. Remove the negativity in your life as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use your smile.&lt;/strong&gt; You don't embark on a quest for your smile just for the sake of beauty -- a noble pursuit, but it's not enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You must use your smile. Use it to express your happiness, to help others, to change the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I smile for kindness in a world that's needlessly barbarous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I smile for inner happiness to stem the tide of seeking happiness through consumerism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I smile for contentment because too many feel a lacking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I smile for compassion because my heart breaks at the cruelty of our species.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I smile for morality in an increasingly unethical world, especially in the growing private sector.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is how I use my smile. How will you use yours?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Thanks again to Leo Babauta for the &lt;a href="http://zenhabits.net/voice/"&gt;original post&lt;/a&gt; of which I mostly copied.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;!-- more end --&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Cookies and Happiness</title><link href="http://joeahand.com/archive/cookies-happiness/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-03-11T17:40:25-06:00</updated><author><name>Joe Hand</name></author><id>tag:joeahand.com,2011-07-22:archive/cookies-happiness/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Baking cookies and finding happiness are mostly the exact same thing.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love baking chocolate chip cookies. For years I have worked to make my cookies better: slightly varying the amount of one ingredient or another, changing the baking time or temperature. Sometimes I fail terribly but most lead me closer to the ideal form of the chocolate chip cookie I am searching for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making cookies involves combining certain ingredients in a certain manner and then acting on that mixture by putting them in the oven. I really like brown sugar and chocolate chips. I also like pizza. If I decided to make cookies replacing flour with pizza and the butter and eggs with more sugar and chocolate, I will end up with a mess in my kitchen and no cookies. I can also create the perfect combination of the necessary ingredients then put them in the microwave to bake. Once again, no cookies and messy kitchen. Perfecting cookies requires perfecting the two essential parts: right ingredients and right baking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Cookies" src="{{" title="site.imgpath }}/cookies_two.jpg &amp;quot;Cookies (Credit:Joe Hand)&amp;quot;;Cookies (Credit:Joe Hand)&amp;quot;" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sadly humans have not always known how to make cookies. We learned, we experimented, and even still some people like one type of cookie over another or less sugar and more chocolate. With happiness we each have our own brand of happiness. But just like you cannot make cookies from pizza, you cannot make happiness from anger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all have a common cupboard from which we pull our ingredients for happiness. Pursuing happiness entails learning which ingredients suit you and acting on those ingredients correctly. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Right mind and right action.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first step in seeking happiness is learning. We first have to learn how negative emotions and behaviors are harmful to us and how positive emotions are helpful. &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Dalai Lama&lt;/strong&gt;, The Art of Happiness &lt;small&gt;(p 38)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Power of Our Mind&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my definitive guide on &lt;a href="{{ site.production_url }}/2011/happiest-place/"&gt;the happiest place on Earth&lt;/a&gt; I told you about your superpower. Humans have the amazing power to change how their brain works and control our own minds. Pretty fascinating really, if you like that neuroscience stuff. The process of learning builds new neural pathways within our brain. In English, that means when we do something a lot our brain gets more efficient working in that way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think about the brain as a network of roads of all sizes and shapes. Our habits, the things we are really good at, use the superhighways that we build over time by doing that action again and again. Meanwhile, if we go to learn a new foreign language we start the process of creating a new road from scratch-- or perhaps you know a few words and have a trail through the woods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Highways of Happiness The first step in discovering happiness is learning. We have taught our brain throughout life to respond in certain ways. If we regularly get angry or upset-- that is the highway in our brain. Meanwhile, the highway of compassion or kindness may be non-existent. Without building the habits of happiness producing thoughts, we cannot expect to be happy.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;The Art of Happiness&lt;/em&gt;, The Dalai Lama describes his reaction to tragic or sad events as causing a "ripple on the surface of an ocean" which does not effect him deep down. He has a happiness super-highway from a lifetime of training. But if you have a disposition towards anger, an event that upsets you skips the happy highway. Instead your thoughts opt for the anger highway because it is the path of least resistance. What could be small ripples turns into bigger and bigger waves the further it proceeds down that road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We must habituate ourselves to create new mental pathways while destroying the old edging us ever closer to the right attitude and therefore happiness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happiness depends more on the inward disposition of mind than on outward circumstances. &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;strong&gt;Benjamin Franklin&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Happiness as a Math Problem&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mathematical beauty of baking attracts me to making cookies. I love to understand how certain ingredients combine with others. I learned how baking soda or baking powder create different reactions, how a yolk or egg whites change the cookies. Then comes the ultimate problem of finding the correct dough size, oven temperature, and baking time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developing the right attitude of happiness works the same way. With every action or thought we have the chance to either lead us closer or move away from our goal. When learning how to be happy, we must realize two things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Positive thoughts and actions generate more positive thoughts and actions. *    Negative thoughts and actions propagate to make us angrier, which leads to more negative actions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Act Now&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For every negative thought you discard and turn into a positive, they do not simply cancel out. Wake up the day and start with a positive thought rather than "ugh morning." This one thought will build on itself turning the day around. Looking at our attitude in relation to others we see the true power of the math of happiness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like in our own minds, negative emotions hurt others and cause more waves of sadness throughout the world. Whereas right mind, right action spreads more happiness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;So which side are you on? Do you want to make your family, your community, and the world more miserable? Or do you want to propagate joy?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="{{ site.production_url }}/cookies/"&gt;Bake some cookies&lt;/a&gt; and spread happiness.&lt;/h3&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Happiness VS Happiness</title><link href="http://joeahand.com/archive/happiness-vs-happiness/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-03-11T17:43:23-06:00</updated><author><name>Joe Hand</name></author><id>tag:joeahand.com,2011-07-21:archive/happiness-vs-happiness/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The battle of genuine happiness and short-term happiness is a battle between beasts and humanity. Which side are you on?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fate of mankind rests on the ability for individuals to pursue happiness. Throughout life people seek to maximize happiness and minimize suffering. But in order to succeed, we must work together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Teaching Happiness Strangely many of us go through more than twelve years of schooling without ever taking a class on how to be happy.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps finding happiness is so easy we do not need to teach it. Or maybe we learn how to be happy in every class because of the importance of happiness. No, the responsibility must fall on parents to teaching kids how to be happy. Well surely happiness cannot be taught, it must be learned from life. Yes, that &lt;em&gt;must&lt;/em&gt; be the answer, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;you learn how to be happy by living&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Therefore, every adult has the duty to show children how to live with genuine happiness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a parent tells a child to eat their veggies or to stop watching TV and do their homework, they do so for the child's own good. Parents force the child to forgo the short-term sensory happiness of television for their long-term happiness. The child may not agree or understand how studying will make them happy, but the adults know. Yet so many adults act like children when seeking happiness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Immediate Happiness Short-term interests plague the country. Looking at any of the problems the country faces-- economic issues, obesity, never-ending legal battles, or war-- adults everywhere pursue the quickest route to pleasure mistaking it for happiness. Sadly, many of these actions ignore the personal and social consequences over time.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our tendency is to rush in and do what seems to promise the shortest route to satisfaction. But in doing so, all too frequently we deprive ourselves of the opportunity for a greater degree of fulfillment. &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Dalai Lama&lt;/strong&gt;, Ethics for the New Millennium &lt;small&gt;(p. 53)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The harmless super-sizing of a meal, fighting for every cent of profit, or neglecting a group of people for the richer lobbyists on the other side-- all of these actions feel great right now. They feel like the path to happiness. But these acts only lead to a desire for more. More food, more money, more power. Gluttony precedes more problems. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;When our indulgence causes suffering for others is when we lose our humanity and become beasts.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Humanity of Genuine Happiness&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genuine happiness. A tricky idea. Too often our desire for satisfaction leads us to satiating our brute impulses, mistaking them for happiness. But rather than seeking happiness externally, we must realize that happiness is not a thing that can be reached but an attitude, a state of being. More importantly, the right actions follow from right attitude. But, here comes the real shocker, right actions help on the path to right attitude. Showing kindness, compassion, love, or concern for others does not diminish the sense of yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether you like it or not, you are dependent on others and others on you. This is the beauty of humanity. If we all work for personal pleasure while making others suffer, we will all suffer. But everyone can pursue happiness together and we can all enjoy a bigger slice of the pie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We come into the world as the result of others' actions. We survive here in dependence on others. Whether we like it or not, there is hardly a moment of our lives when we do not benefit from others' activities. For this reason, it is hardly surprising that most of our happiness arises in the context of our relationships with others. &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Dalai Lama&lt;/strong&gt;, Ethics for the New Millennium &lt;small&gt;(p. 62)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Act Now&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developing a sense of inner peace and the right attitude can take years or a lifetime. It can only be achieved through patience and hard work. But nothing stops you from helping others on the path to genuine happiness. The remarkable thing is, it will help you along your path too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Worry less&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; about your own suffering or sadness. * &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Show concern&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for a friend or stranger. *  Guide them towards happiness with &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;compassion and kindness&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. *  Realize you have just taken a step towards your own happiness.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Do you want to be an animal or a human?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you going to make your inner child eats all the veggies before it leaves the table? Or learn something rather than watch TV?&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Dangers of Reaching The National Bullshit Ceiling</title><link href="http://joeahand.com/archive/defaulting-reality/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-03-11T17:43:18-06:00</updated><author><name>Joe Hand</name></author><id>tag:joeahand.com,2011-07-20:archive/defaulting-reality/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The nation is reaching the &lt;strong&gt;National Bullshit Ceiling&lt;/strong&gt;. Young generations are becoming completely dismissive of politics leaving a nation without leaders. Without bold truth-telling action, the nation will "default on reality". But that would just be the beginning of our problems. Future generations may become completely dismissive of politics leaving a nation without leaders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Daily Show recently discussed the National Bullshit Ceiling and the threat it poses to the country. Daily Show correspondent, Jason Jones, warned us of the impending doom if we pass the limit:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we reach the point where the amount of bullshit exceeds the amount of things we will effectively default on reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We already see how this political culture affects our current environment. Our representatives argue with false pretenses. We disregard the truth for the sake of profit or ideology. Individuals now get identified by their parties not what they represent. However, the real harm will be passed on to future generations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The true damage of the current political culture comes in the form of the dissatisfaction and ambivalence of young voters, which I myself am a part of. I find myself increasingly discouraged by politics. I do not see significant progress being made and am especially frustrated by how we value short-term rewards over long-term investments. I will be the first to admit, I am as guilty in my apathy as any other young voter. I have only been motivated to vote in one of the six elections I could vote it. Take a guess which one (hint: it involved the promise of change).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the short-term, young generations will be poorly represented and discriminated against in policies. But long-term effects will be catastrophic. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;As a generation we are being raised with a distrust towards politicians&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. We see a lack of ethics our leaders and develop a pessimistic attitude, sometimes completely dismissing anything political. What will happen when the young become the old and the country needs people to run it? Who should we look to as role models?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started this post with the idea of motivating myself and other young voters to care about politics. As I continue in my exploration, I keep wondering, why should we care? The future is a long ways away, yet many of the politicians do not think beyond the past. How could they possibly help us? But it's we who need to help them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Beasts of Politics&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Politics devoid of ethics does not further human welfare, and life without morality reduces humans to the level of beasts. This leads some of us to refrain from politics altogether, but politics is not axiomatically dirty. Rather, the misguided instruments of our political culture have distorted our high ideals and nobel aspirations. &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Dalai Lama&lt;/strong&gt;, How to See Yourself as Your Really Are&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our political culture is one of beasts. There is no doubting that. But by refusing to engage our leaders, we are just as guilty of driving our country towards failure. We need to take initiative and hold our leaders accountable. We need to set an example of truth telling and living with integrity. Every interaction, every discussion, every decision we make either compounds the problems or helps to solve them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title='By Benjamin Franklin [Public domain], via Wikimedia Commons' href='http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Benjamin_Franklin_-_Join_or_Die.jpg'&gt;&lt;img width='500' style="margin:0 auto; display:block;" alt='Benjamin Franklin - Join or Die' src='http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/9/9c/Benjamin_Franklin_-_Join_or_Die.jpg/500px-Benjamin_Franklin_-_Join_or_Die.jpg'/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Take Initiative, Stop the Bullshit&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Daily Show clip, Jason Jones called for action. He proposed a solution of "replacing shit with FARTS from our BUTTS." Beyond the obvious comical genius here, the Daily Show team was spot on calling for:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="no-bullet" style="position:absolute; margin-left:200px; margin-top:0px; "&gt;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;b class="big"&gt;B&lt;/b&gt;old&lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;b class="big"&gt;U&lt;/b&gt;ncompromising&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b class="big"&gt;T&lt;/b&gt;ruth&lt;/li&gt;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;b class="big"&gt;T&lt;/b&gt;elling&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ul class="no-bullet"&gt;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b class="big"&gt;F&lt;/b&gt;actual&lt;/li&gt;     &lt;li&gt;&lt;b class="big"&gt;A&lt;/b&gt;ssessments of&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;b class="big"&gt;R&lt;/b&gt;eality based&lt;/li&gt;   &lt;li&gt;&lt;b class="big"&gt;T&lt;/b&gt;ruths&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We do not just need this from our politicians, we need this to permeate throughout our society.  Our apathy encourages this culture to strengthen and infect more of our citizens and representatives. Start a revolution by having the courage to stand up and demand an end to bullshit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Act with integrity, act boldly, challenge the bullshit.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The full Daily Show clip for those who need some laughs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;object width="512" height="288" class="add-bottom" style="margin:0 auto; display:block;"&gt;&lt;param name="movie" value="http://www.hulu.com/embed/3g4uGkZQ-7cKvGSD4KVFyw"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed src="http://www.hulu.com/embed/3g4uGkZQ-7cKvGSD4KVFyw" type="application/x-shockwave-flash"  width="512" height="288" allowFullScreen="true"&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>The Only Place In The World Where You Can Find Happiness</title><link href="http://joeahand.com/archive/happiest-place/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-03-11T17:34:41-06:00</updated><author><name>Joe Hand</name></author><id>tag:joeahand.com,2011-07-19:archive/happiest-place/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Welcome to the most definitive guide ever about the happiest place on Earth. Inside I offer a simple three step fix to finally reach the ultimate goal in life.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After reading through top ten list after top ten list, a book about the happiest countries on Earth, surveys about happiness, and even visiting some happy places, I finally found it, &lt;strong&gt;the happiest place in the World&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Searching Google for &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;happiest place in world&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; yields almost three million results. Millions of top ten lists fight to reach the top ten spots on the first search page. A self-proclaimed grump, Eric Weiner, even took it upon himself to fly around the world searching for the world's happiest place in the book &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/044669889X/ref=as*li*qf*sp*asin*tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=smijoe-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=217145&amp;amp;creative=399369&amp;amp;creativeASIN=044669889X"&gt;The Geography of Bliss&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nine different countries and one happy US city later he concludes the destination of happiness can be reached through many paths: &amp;gt;Money matters, but less than we think and not in the way that we think. Family is important. So are friends. Envy is toxic. So is excessive thinking. Beaches are optional. Trust is not. Neither is gratitude.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With so many different ways to happiness how can you know what path is right for you? Perhaps it is not about the journey but the people you meet along the way. The author reconsiders one of the people he met on his journey and decides "happiness is completely and utterly intertwined with other people... happiness is not a noun or verb. It's a conjunction. Connective tissue." So it must be more about the people than the actual place. Now we are left to wonder how to find these relationships that make us happy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even after trotting the globe trying to discover happiness he ends his journey "not 100 percent happy. Closer to feevty-feevty." Unfortunately, no one informed him of the true, happiest place on earth. You cannot find it on any of the top ten lists on Google. And no, it is not Disney World.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Way to Happiness&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I offer you a simple three step process for the way to happiness:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Buy a plane ticket to Denmark. 2.   Pack your stuff, fly there. 3.  Arrive in world's happiest place, be happy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Foolproof right? Year after year Denmark ranks as the "&lt;a href="http://news.bbc.co.uk/2/hi/7487143.stm"&gt;world's happiest nation&lt;/a&gt;." So anyone who goes there must be happy. It's the rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, you cannot suddenly become happy by just arriving in Denmark and any fool knows this. &lt;strong&gt;To find true happiness, it must come from within&lt;/strong&gt;. Sure you can enjoy a beautiful place, wonderful food, or a great concert. But unless you have the right attitude, nothing external will make you happy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no way to happiness. Happiness is the way. &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thich Nhat Hanh&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Cultivating Happiness&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I talked briefly at the end of my last post about planting the seed for this attitude. First you must be aware of what you can and cannot control. Things happen. Great things, terrible things. Unless you are a wizard or have a time machine you are powerless to change the past. But you still have a great power within you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You have the power to control your thoughts. Every event summons a reaction within your mind. Start to nurture the attitude that you have the superpower of authority over your mind. Be attentive to your immediate response to any external event. Here is your homework assignment:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Acknowledge your knee-jerk thoughts, becoming aware of them as they develop. *  Remember that you have a superpower. With that power you can control your mind. *   Finally, let the thoughts pass by, as if they were a small cloud in an otherwise blue sky.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Keep the Sky Blue&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cultivate a blue sky in your mind&lt;/em&gt;. Actively strive to keep that sky clear of nasty thoughts and intentions-- &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;for that is the only place in the world where you can find happiness&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. See the clouds, say hello if you like, then watch as they drift out of sight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Find Your Smile, Find Happiness&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the author's final leg of his journey, he recounts a serendipitous meeting with the airport bartender. The bartender's name, of course, "Happy." Without hesitation the author asks him what the secret of happiness is. His answer, simple: &amp;gt;"Just keep on smiling. Even when you're sad. Keep on smiling."&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Create Strength by Investing in Talent</title><link href="http://joeahand.com/archive/strengths/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-03-11T17:33:03-06:00</updated><author><name>Joe Hand</name></author><id>tag:joeahand.com,2011-07-17:archive/strengths/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The book Strength Finder 2.0 develops the idea of maximizing productivity through investment in talents. By understanding your talents you can create strengths while also being more engaged in your work. A greater awareness of my strengths will help me achieve more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Strength Equation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the book, Strength Finder 2.0, Tom Rath introduces the three concepts of &lt;strong&gt;talent, investment,&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;strength&lt;/strong&gt;. By &lt;em&gt;investing&lt;/em&gt; in our &lt;em&gt;talents&lt;/em&gt; we create &lt;em&gt;strengths&lt;/em&gt;. He argues that spending time developing our weaknesses gives less return than developing our talents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our economy drastically underutilizes our skills because we fail to focus on our strengths. When you manager fails to focus on your strength you are likely to be disengaged at work. By investing in our weaknesses employers increase the chances that we will become bored and inefficient at work. Rather, Rath suggests we need to focus on our talents to become the best we can be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You &lt;strong&gt;cannot&lt;/strong&gt; be anything you want to be -- but you &lt;strong&gt;can&lt;/strong&gt; be a lot more of who you already are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key is thinking in terms of talents and strengths, not knowledge and skills. By applying your talents to your interests you can build strengths, regardless of the area of study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Talent and Investment&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we think of the word talent we often think of people who are exceptionally good at something-- Michael Jordan was a talented basketball player or Jimi Hendrix was a talented guitarist. Thinking about your own life, you may be a talented cook or writer. The book defines talent slightly differently from this common conception.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of our common definition, consider talent "a natural way of thinking, feeling, or behaving." While this covers a great deal, I want to focus on the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;natural&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; part of the definition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People relate to and understand the world through different means. These ways to relate, or talents, are innate to who we are -- our natural talents. Rather than forcing everyone to conform to one way of thinking, by strengthening our natural abilities we can achieve more and be happier in the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This departure differs dramatically from the usual understanding of education. Education works on conforming everyone through the same methods to reach the same goals. By teaching everyone the same we are dramatically reducing the return on that education while boring people to death. Sounds like a lose-lose for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By investing in people in an individualized way, we create engaged students. Not only does this make the process of education more fun, but we get better results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Strengths&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Strengths require both talent and investment. Anybody can develop strengths in any venue of talent. But by focusing on our top talents we maximize the time we spend honing our skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discovering our strengths also makes it easier for us to work with passion and actively engage in something. So without further ado... here are my results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;My Strengths&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The online assessment takes about thirty minutes and is only available if you buy the book (great marketing). Along with your generic theme descriptions, they give a detailed summary of personal strengths. These are my top five strengths:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learner&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Futuristic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Relator&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Intellection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Responsibility&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rest of the post I will be trying to understand more about myself, my strengths, and how I can apply them. None of them were super surprising. The relator I quested a bit until reading further into my personal summary, then it made sense. There are three sections of the report: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;awareness, application&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;achievement&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. I will discuss each theme, then move on to the next section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Awareness&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Learner&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Generic Description:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People who are especially talented in the Learner theme have a great desire to learn and want to continuously improve. In particular, the process of learning, rather than the outcome, excites them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sounds just like me! I love learning. I am a sponge for all information from every source. I always loved school and have continued to learn since leaving school. The personalized description was more interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Personal Insights&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whole thing is quite long, so no reason to post here. But I will pick out the things that I am most curious about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You appear to study human beings the way others study for final tests. Your approach is direct. Your gaze is intense Your interest is sincere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is great! I am not sure about whether this is how I really approach others. I am usually a pretty shy person, naturally quite introverted. The description talks a lot unusual individuals capture my attention and I become curious about them. I will need to work on developing this part of my learning talents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chances are good that you will your mind with new ideas by asking questions, reading, studying, observing or listening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ummmm. Talk about generic statements. How else could one fill their mind?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of your strengths, you yearn to know a lot. It makes little sense to you to skim through a book and read only the highlights. You delve more deeply into intriguing subjects than most people do. You love to gather all kinds of information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Definitely true. One look at my bookshelves reveal this. I have a broad range of topics that have struck my interest. I usually read enough about the topics until I feel like I have a solid understanding of the issues then move on. Usually I start with the more important and influential books on the subject and move toward a fringe or two that really peaks my learning curiosity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For learner, I need to work on developing my ability to learn from other people the most. The report also mentions my ability to give counsel to others. Something that I enjoy doing, but do not actually get the chance to much right now. So, reaching out more and developing those relationships may help me build that strength.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Futuristic&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Generic Description:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People who are especially talented in the Futuristic theme are inspired by the future and what could be. They inspire others with their visions of the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Always thinking about the future, but I need to work on inspiring others with my visions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Personal Insights&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of your strengths, you invest considerable time creating the future of your own choosing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am hoping to create my own future as we speak. The most important thing I want to do is invest in my strengths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Driven by your talents, you feel enthusiastic about life when you contemplate everything you can accomplish in the coming months, years, or decades. You probably need to know what the future holds before you can concentrate on today's activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Very true. Sometimes it gets to the point where I get little done if I do not know how this helps the future. This can definitely make it difficult to get some things done. But...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You think in terms of possibilities. This allows you to recover from setbacks, problems, disappointments, or even disasters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The upside of looking to the future. There are speed bumps, but they are nothing compared to the long term.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's very likely that you sense your life has deep meaning. With remarkable vividness, you often imagine where you will be, what you will be doing, and what you have the ability to accomplish in the coming months, years, or decades. Your dreams of tomorrow are very alive in your mind today... The question you must answer is this: "How far into the future can I think before my ideas start becoming vague or uninspiring?"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Definitely the part of futuristic that I struggle with. I need to balance having a long term vision with the ability to motivate myself to get there. I often abandon projects or areas of study when I get frustrated with the short term and lack the overall vision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Relator&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Generic Description:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People who are especially talented in the Relator theme enjoy close relationships with others. They find deep satisfaction in working hard with friends to achieve a goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Finding New Music</title><link href="http://joeahand.com/archive/new-music/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-02-09T03:46:54-07:00</updated><author><name>Joe Hand</name></author><id>tag:joeahand.com,2011-07-11:archive/new-music/</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Enjoying the Music&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I listen to music a lot. While I am not a huge music buff, I like to have stuff playing while I work, cook, clean, or just hang around my house.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Music becoming digital has led to a near infinite selection. Music listeners love this. But it also means more choices, probably &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2010/02/27/your-money/27shortcuts.html"&gt;too many choices&lt;/a&gt;. In my search for music, I would go through the same one of these three directions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find song I want to hear, use iTunes Genius.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select lots of songs I do not own using GrooveShark.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choose artist I like, use Pandora.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of these services are great. But each has its own drawback. Worst of all, none of them really lead to new music. Reading the blog endorsing the power of new music encouraged me to start my search. I wanted to find something that was not time consuming, had plenty of new music, and some old favorites mixed in. After trying a variety of sources, I finally found the goldmine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Oldie-But-Goodie Sources&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My usual sources for music are great. But they make it hard to find new music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;iTunes Genius&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The limits and benefits of Genius do not take long to figure out. Great for listening to genres of music you own. Not good for finding new music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love the iTunes Genius button. Since they came up with it I basically stopped making playlists. That combined with the time my music library got wiped out losing all my old playlists and ratings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use genius when I know what I want to listen to. Let's say I go with a classic like &lt;em&gt;Crosstown Traffic&lt;/em&gt; by Jimi Hendrix. iTunes genius gives me a nice selection of rock mixed with some newer pop stuff. All songs I like, definitely a good playlist. But the problem-- I need to own all the music. So then I move on to GrooveShark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;GrooveShark&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For people who do not know about GrooveShark, I encourage you to check it out now: &lt;a href="http://grooveshark.com/"&gt;GrooveShark.com&lt;/a&gt;. Two things about GrooveShark encourage me to use it over and over again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create playlists from many many songs I do not own.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find music from lists of popular songs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mostly use this when I know what I want to listen to. Discovering new music on the poplar list is hit or miss. Otherwise you have to know which new music to search for, defeating the point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GrooveShark also has a radio feature, but in my experience it does not compare to Pandora.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Pandora&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course I have a &lt;strong&gt;Jimi Hendrix&lt;/strong&gt; station of Pandora. And the station is great. But the music stays along the same lines as iTunes. I get some music that I do not own and perhaps a few new songs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I want to branch out I can start a station with a newer artist. Without a doubt, I have discovered great new music through Pandora. However the stations get stale regardless of where you start. A computer can only reach so far into new genres. I also find myself hitting skip until I find a comfortable song, defeating the whole point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After creating about 30 Pandora stations I became frustrated and began my search.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Search for New Music&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above three sources of music have provided most of my music the last two years or so. I rarely reach out to find new music. When I started, I realized I had no clue where to turn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Asking Friends&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None of my friends really seek out new music. Lots of people do, I just do not know them. If you know the right people this will probably be a great source.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For decades new music gained popularity through the radio, so I moved there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Streaming Radio&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do not own a radio, limiting me to streaming radio. Luckily most radio stations stream now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love advertisements as much as the next person. So, I chose to stick with public radio streams only. My dad works in public radio so he had plenty of good suggestions for me:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;KEXP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Current&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WXPN&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WBEZ&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NPR Music&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lots more...&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each station offers different types of music during the day. Without knowledge of what shows were closer to the kind of music I enjoyed I became frustrated. Plenty of stations also offer streaming of individual shows that I could match with my interests. That conflicts my goal of being time efficient though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Podcasts&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The jump from streaming radio to podcasts was easy. Lots of stations offer their shows as podcasts. But once again I ran into the problem of too many choices. Tons of music podcasts fill the iTunes directory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Staring at the list of top music podcasts in iTunes is a strange experience. I started listening to some from the radio stations I enjoyed more. The experience was again hit or miss. Unfortunately, somewhere in the strange mix of podcasts in the top 10, I missed &lt;em&gt;NPR's All Songs Considered.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Goldmine&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;All Songs Considered&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After downloading and listening to some other podcasts, I returned to the top 10 disappointed and looking for more. Finally I found it, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;NPR's All Songs Considered&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: the perfect combination of new music and old favorites spiced up with great stories and music knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am really happy with the podcast because not only do I get to hear new music, but the hosts have a vast understanding of the music. Unlike Pandora, the podcasts can jump from one genre to another while still having a common theme. And in the process of hearing music I am also learning about music-- the best of both worlds!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have listened to about 30 of the 300 old episodes and am looking forwards to the rest. Best of all, there is a 24/7 music stream if I ever get tired of the commentary.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Starting with A Clean Slate</title><link href="http://joeahand.com/archive/clean-slate/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-03-11T17:32:29-06:00</updated><author><name>Joe Hand</name></author><id>tag:joeahand.com,2011-07-08:archive/clean-slate/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Washing away the old and preparing for the new. Before on this page there were a couple blog posts, but nothing worth talking about. Seth Godin &lt;a href="http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths*blog/2011/07/put-your-name-on-it-1.html"&gt;posted today&lt;/a&gt; about &lt;em&gt;putting your name on it&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"If you can't sign it, don't ship it."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The things I wrote before were not worth signing. This decreased my motivation to write new posts. So here is to starting fresh--creating something where I will proudly display my seal of approval.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Riding the wave.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This fresh start comes on the wave of another new project. Two weeks ago I began a project at &lt;a href="http://smilingjoe.com"&gt;SmilingJoe.com&lt;/a&gt; called &lt;strong&gt;Experiments in Kindness&lt;/strong&gt;. I feel a strange force pulling me forwards. Bringing me towards new opportunities, encouraging me to explore new ways of thinking. It is exciting yet scary. I only hope I can stay above the surf.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But getting knocked down may be a better experience than riding the wave itself. So then I look forwards to whatever lies ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Failure is the opportunity to begin again more intelligently." &amp;gt; &amp;gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Henry Ford&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Yummy Chocolate Chip Cookies</title><link href="http://joeahand.com/archive/cookies/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-02-09T03:34:06-07:00</updated><author><name>Joe Hand</name></author><id>tag:joeahand.com,2011-06-21:archive/cookies/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ever since I can remember I made Chocolate Chip Cookies. Ten years ago I discovered a recipe I really liked, memorized it, and spent the next ten years experimenting on slight variations. I always get lots of people asking me for my recipe, so here it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The real secret is not what you put in the cookies, but how you make them. So be sure to add lots of love!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Cookie Dough" src="{{" title="site.imgpath }}/cookie_dough.jpg &amp;quot;Dough Preparing for Battle (Credit:Joe Hand)&amp;quot;;Dough Preparing for Battle (Credit:Joe Hand)&amp;quot;" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Chocolate Chip Cookies&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follow the directions, make yummy cookies, and share them with your friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Ingredients (double or triple as necessary):&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 Cups Flour&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1/2 tsp Sea Salt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1/2 tsp Baking Soda&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 c Brown Sugar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1/2 c White Sugar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3/4 c Butter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 egg&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 egg yolk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 tbsp vanilla&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Directions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start by getting all of your ingredients out in one place. That way you will not forget anything. Put things away after each step and make cleaning so much easier!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mix dry stuff in bowl, set aside.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 Cups Flour&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1/2 tsp Sea Salt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1/2 tsp Baking Soda&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mix sugars and butter in new bowl. Melted butter is easier but changes how dough bakes (&lt;strong&gt;See Note&lt;/strong&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 c Brown Sugar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1/2 c White Sugar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3/4 c Butter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mix in eggs and vanilla.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 egg&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 egg yolk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 tbsp vanilla&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add dry stuff into wet about 1/2 cup at a time and mix with a gentle force.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add chocolate chips (about 1 cup but really a personal preference here).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Place on cookie sheet. Make whatever size you want. Bake at 325 for 12ish minutes, until edges are browned.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Cookies" src="{{" title="site.imgpath }}/cookies_med.jpg &amp;quot;Cookies (Credit:Joe Hand)&amp;quot;;Cookies (Credit:Joe Hand)&amp;quot;" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; The dough (and therefore cookies) is much better if put in the fridge for 24-48hrs wrapped in plastic/tightly covered, especially if you melt the butter. Melted butter makes the dough little tough to work with immediately. Take it out of the fridge 30min before you plan on baking the cookies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good luck and enjoy the cookies.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Future of Books is in the Container</title><link href="http://joeahand.com/archive/future-books/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-03-11T17:36:50-06:00</updated><author><name>Joe Hand</name></author><id>tag:joeahand.com,2011-05-03:archive/future-books/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I feel like the biggest driving issue with digital books is the container. Once the container gets standardized, the content and usage can become more standardized. So I guess the question is how to you become the standard container for a type of information. I would imagine the book had some sort of competition, people who bound the pages in a different way or presented ideas differently, right? It does not really sound right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wonder if we are too stuck on the idea of a &lt;em&gt;book&lt;/em&gt;. Does a remix machine need even to have that idea. There is definitely some idea of cognitive location within an argument. Without knowing how long the argument lasts it may be difficult to focus or understand what the writer is saying. But how can we say that when have books that range from 50 pages to thousands. We have messages that are limited to 140 characters and messages that are unlimited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When information first started to be communicated over wires a new neo-language had to be invented to convey the message. Then in order to protect privacy and save money people went further to create secret languages on top of this neo-language. That is a pretty powerful idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just by having this standard means of communication people were able to be so innovative around it. Was it the standardization or the uniqueness or what? It seems like the morse-code telegraph broke so many boundaries it had to be a hot bed ripe for innovation. So how do you create that kind of atmosphere around a product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does it tell a story? Or connect people? Or just provide economic advantage?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe our thinking is indeed too narrow. Is the portal or the container more important. I think of Google as a portal. iTunes is more of a container. Both are powerful market movers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google has used the portal to become a container for other types of goods. What gave them an advantage here?&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Finding passion</title><link href="http://joeahand.com/archive/finding-passion/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-03-11T17:35:41-06:00</updated><author><name>Joe Hand</name></author><id>tag:joeahand.com,2011-05-02:archive/finding-passion/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Both Ken Robinson and Seth Godin preach similar sentiments. Each encourages us to start doing something we love and share that gift with others. By doing something we love we become more energized by doing that thing. That allows us to share even more with the world. At the same time, when we do something we love, the opportunities change in our lives. By living through our passion we can reshape our lives to become something better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;'Be the change you want to see in the world' -Ghandi&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like an angry person cannot bring world peace, you must follow your passion to live a fulfilling life. The difficulty comes in finding what that passion is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where have I found myself to be passionate? When have I done something where I lose all track of time? What activities give me energy?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are all very interesting questions that are difficult to answer. I can think back about what I have done in the past that fueled me, but what if that has changed. I can think about what I am excited about in the future, but is that enough to drive my life forwards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am passionate about happiness in a way that others do not seem to be. I am passionate about being myself, caring, kindness. I strive to be the best person I can be, and I enjoy spending time understanding how I can do that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love new ideas. I love seeing new ideas change others even more. But how can that help me find my tribe?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe I should have been an engineer or architect. What if that is what I was meant to do? How would my life path look different had I pursued that passion?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to write more today. Yesterday I proposed a post about the overarching goal of Seamless. Perhaps that is too grand of a topic. I am distracted. The resistance is pulling me away. Should I give in? Should I keep writing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe my passion is just as the quote from Ghandi above. Perhaps I can find my passion by being the change I want to see in the world.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Health and Pilates</title><link href="http://joeahand.com/archive/pilates/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-03-11T17:48:25-06:00</updated><author><name>Joe Hand</name></author><id>tag:joeahand.com,2011-04-17:archive/pilates/</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Intro to Pilates&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joseph Pilates founded pilates to help bed ridden patients begin injury recoveries. Bed ridden or not, I have my share of injuries and imbalances. By focusing on moving from your powerhouse, Pilates helps teach your body proper alignment and movement using your core muscles- a powerful idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I first tried Pilates when my mom gifted me with a private session with her teacher. Walking into a Pilates studio is intimidating. There are a myriad of strange machines with straps and springs. There are all sorts of balls and oddly shaped equipment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first lesson was an awakening. I had never felt that sense of control while feeling so out of control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Using your powerhouse&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you had a powerhouse why would you not use it? Well, good news, you do! The powerhouse idea in Pilates establishes the base of every movement. Imagine a rectangle going from your pelvic floor to your shoulders enclosing everything in between. That is your powerhouse. Deep inside your core you have hugely strong and expansive muscles that pull everything from your pelvis, spine, and organs together. Pilates teaches you to initiate each movement with that base and then engage the isolated muscles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moving from the powerhouse is a powerful idea. By requiring that movement start and end in the center of the body- Pilates teaches you to move with utmost control, focus, and breath.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Pilates for Men, the book&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After some major injuries I came back to Pilates with the hope of becoming injury free. I failed then and that is why I return once again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal this time is much more substantial and focused. My overriding goal is to become injury free- and stay that way. After looking through the book I understood that by making it to the end I would achieve that goal. So I set up a fake goal. I want to become an advanced Pilates and Yoga dude. In the process I hope to rid myself of injuries and gain a new sense of bodily balance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Dunking&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end, I really want to dunk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The basketball rim sits at 10 feet high. The ball either goes in or it doesn't There is some fantasy aspect about dunking. The image of flying high to pack it down is unyielding. Always a little bit higher. You either get there, or you fail.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Poking the Box</title><link href="http://joeahand.com/archive/poke-the-box/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-03-11T17:27:30-06:00</updated><author><name>Joe Hand</name></author><id>tag:joeahand.com,2011-04-16:archive/poke-the-box/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have been struggling to start. When I do start, I lack the patience to finish. This blog for example: I excitedly created the site, wrote the first post, and then waited, but nothing happened. For some reason the blog did not blossom like I had imagined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ben Franklin knew how to start his writing career. At thirteen, Franklin started by rewriting other's work. He never stopped. Shortly after he was submitting letters to the local paper under a fake name. Throughout his life he pushed new ideas forward. Ben Franklin initiated, just look at the list: successful printing shop, library, volunteer firehouses, safer fireplaces, bifocals, electricity. By poking the box, he became one of the most influential people of his era.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Poke the box&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In his book, Seth Godin stresses starting and shipping - a blog post, a worldwide revolution, or helping a stranger unprompted - ship something new however large or small. The default, the safe thing to do is nothing. If you create enough then you will fail. Leading the reader by the hand and acknowledging all bad that may come, the book forces the reader take action. Without failing there cannot be success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout reading the idea of creative destruction was in my mind. Joseph Schumpeter proposed entrepreneurs drove the growth of the economy through creative destruction. Entrepreneurs are driven to markets where monopolies are coasting on old technological innovation. All of the new entrants attempt to create a more efficient technology. One successful innovation topples the old monopoly while creating a new one. The growth of the economy depends on the number and success rate of the entrepreneurs. With barriers to innovation at a low, this idea is more powerful than ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Creative Destruction of the self&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creative destruction has always described the economy, but what about a person? When I lift weights- that is creative destruction- I am destroying my muscle fibers to encourage them to grow back stronger. This is what Seth proposes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Create a new you: start&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week I made the goal of doing getting 100% injury free. Using my awesome book, &lt;em&gt;The Complete Book of &lt;strong&gt;Pilates for Men&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, I planned my first mini-goal. I scoped out the &lt;em&gt;advanced reformer on the mat workout&lt;/em&gt; and set it in my sights. About half the exercises looked impossible, but not quite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Start small&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started with a simple 20 minute workout every morning, the &lt;em&gt;beginner mat workout&lt;/em&gt;. A huge red X went on my calendar after each completed workout, the Jerry Seinfeld method. One week later I feel a bit stronger. But I really need to push the box.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Deliver on that new you: ship&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creating a plan and starting is good. The real goodness comes from shipping. In one month my calendar may be full of red- what then? Well, I will have a stronger core, maybe I will love Pilates or hate it. Cool, that does not sound so bad. In one year my calendar may be full of red- what then? My body will be stronger than ever. Even a third of the way through the book, my body moving in a way that was once impossible. Down the road, when I am 80, I may even be doing the stuff Joseph Pilates did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Failure or success is irrelevant if you progress&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In committing to do Pilates for thirty days I know I will push the box. So what if the Pilates space in my box never expands again. It has been pushed, it was not worth it, my box expanded and I moved to push elsewhere- maybe yoga. Then the process starts all over again. Always moving outwards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I imagine myself testing to optimize my personal self. The goal of my life is to expand. Right now, I need to find where there are maximum returns, just as the entrepreneurs do in the creative destruction economy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The markets where monopolies sit tantalize entrepreneurs. If they succeed in overthrowing the monopoly the rewards are great. They become the new monopoly. Markets where profits are small or levels of technology superior provide no motivation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Where is your personal monopoly?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part of you is stuck in routine. It refuses to change. You act the same way in certain situations, always acknowledge people in the same manner, or pick the same thing every time. Just once try act differently, see how it feels, let it soak in. Rinse and repeat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the economy one entrepreneur succeeds because so many others fail. If it was one entrepreneur vs one monopoly, I'd put my money on the monopoly. One million entrepreneurs and it is a different story. That is why the value comes from poking the box again and again not doing it once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Everyone poke together now&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is scary to think about a world where every person is as determined as Ben Franklin was. Scary because of the amount of astonishing things that could be done. While each person has their own box to push, it is not all that gets pushed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;One box growing encourages another&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One day someone in the neighborhood decides to push; she smile and says hello to everyone passing- a stranger smiles back. She watches his box expand as he walks away. A smile is one thing, but Ben Franklin reached for much more than just kindness towards strangers. At first he pushed to expand his own box, then that of the local paper, he did not stop until he made a huge dent in all of mankind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With each small poke the boxes that enclose us grow; first the box of your house, then your neighborhood, and if you poke hard enough eventually you will push the box of all humanity further.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>First Post</title><link href="http://joeahand.com/archive/first-post/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-03-11T17:29:54-06:00</updated><author><name>Joe Hand</name></author><id>tag:joeahand.com,2011-03-30:archive/first-post/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I struggle to comprehend how our country has changed since its founding. Reading the autobiography of Ben Franklin I am struck by the amount of civility that abounds in the congress. People were actually pleasant enough to argue about an issue, compromise, then create a document that everyone liked. Has the character of our person's changed that dramatically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This country lacks a solid moral compass. Our effects create the future yet we discard any ideas that take that into account. Everything is about the present. What helps me and now is not soon enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can our youth understand this idea if the majority of adults refuse to accept the notion?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a moral struggle going on in our country. The right is scared of changes, progress, and new ideas. The left is afraid of shit I dunno- maybe how our country is spiraling down and down with every new law passed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our country was founded on compromise, new ideas, and a basic moral constitution. Where did those founding principles go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would we be able to recognize the benefit of a public hospital or library today. Could those institutions be created in this political climate? I doubt it. The public hospital first proposed required that the government match and private contributions. That would never happen in a million years. What changed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ben Franklin had an interesting line in his autobiography about people's unwillingness to change. He understood that accepting new ideas is difficult unless the situation forces it. How can we put ourselves in situations to force new ideas while remaining comfortable- or is that even possible. Perhaps it is the trickiness of situations that allow us to see situations in new light.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Franklin was a powerful man, yet he did not act is such a way. Franklin wanted everyone to accept an idea before it was put into practice. He was able to be convincing be trying to find what that person's individual interest or notion was. He then worked to tie that to the big picture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps, we just lack that sort of big picture thinkers. Franklin was able to do a remarkable job of bringing everyone together without forcing one side to concede more than another. He wanted the largest benefit to the public in each situation.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry></feed>